Another concept that is important to understand for the way we're going to create data structures is
the concept of pointers.
And to explain this, I'm going to start with something that is not a pointer and then compare it to
something that does use a pointer.
So we're going to have a variable, number one, and we're going to set it equal to 11 and then we'll
have another variable NUM two.
And we're going to set this equal to number one, which obviously makes Numata equal to 11.
Now, to see how something that is not a pointer works, let's flip over to VSG code.
OK, so up here, we have someone equal to 11 and number two, equal to number one, and then we're
just going to print these out.
So I'll run this.
And we have before the value is updated, number one is 11 and number two is 11.
Now I'm going to paste in some new code.
And all we're going to do here is set Namwon equal to 22.
And then we're going to print this out again.
OK, so he can see over here after value was updated, no one is now 22, but number two is still 11.
OK, so let's flip back.
So when you set numb to equal to number one, these are not linked forever, you are just initializing
them to with the value of no one at the time.
If you change them, one number two stays with the value that it was initialized with.
And that is what happens when you're working with something that is not using a pointer.
Now, let's compare this to something that does use a pointer.
We're going to say dictionary one equals this dictionary and we'll use the value of 11 again, but inside
of a dictionary.
So when you have something set equal to a dictionary, it is a pointer to the dictionary.
You are saying dictionary one points to this dictionary.
So if you say dictionary two equals dictionary one.
If you did this the same way that we did when just using a number, then it would look like this dictionary
too would point to its own dictionary with value of eleven.
But that is not what happens when you're using a pointer.
When you set dictionary to equal to dictionary one, you are literally saying dictionary to points to
the exact same dictionary in memory as dictionary one.
So now let's go take a look at this NVS code.
OK, so we have a dictionary, one equal to that dictionary with value equal to 11, and then we set
dictionary to equal to dictionary one and then here we're going to print all of this out.
So let's run this.
And before the value is updated, Dictionary one has a valuable 11 dictionary, too, has a valuable
luvin.
Now, I'm going to paste in some code here.
And this is changing the value of dictionary one to 22, so now when we run this.
You can see where dictionary one and dictionary to have value of 22, and the reason being is they are
both pointing to that same dictionary.
If we change dictionary one over here, that's the one the dictionary, too, is pointing to.
So what updates that?
OK, so let's flip back over.
And the value of dictionary one and dictionary to have both changed to 22.
So there are a couple of other concepts I want to show here.
Let's just say we have another one called Dictionary three.
If we set dictionary to equal the dictionary three, we're just going to redirect that pointer down
here so these pointers can be redirected like this.
And this idea of having a pointer point to a new place is a concept that we're going to use a lot in
the data structure section.
So that's the first concept that I wanted to talk about there.
But there's another concept.
In order to explain this, let's set dictionary one equal to dictionary to like this.
Now, all of these variables are pointing down here, so now the question is what happens to this dictionary
here?
The only way you can get to this is through appointer, once you have moved all the pointers away from
this, you no longer have a way of getting to it.
So what Python will do to free this memory up?
With items that are not usable, is it will run a process called garbage collection to remove this.
All right, and that is our overview.
Of pointers.